Guide to the Henry David papers, 1943-2010 RL.11256
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Henry David papers
1943-2010, bulk 1970s-1990s
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Sallie Bingham Center for Women's History and Culture
David, Henry Philip, 1923-
RL.11256
140 Linear Feet 166 boxes
Henry Philip David (1923-2009) was a pioneering researcher in the field of reproductive behavior and public policy. He is notable for his longitudinal studies on the psychological aspects of abortion, as well as his extensive international collaboration and research. He was the founder (1972) and director of the Transnational Family Research Institute in Bethesda, MD. He wrote and edited 17 books and authored or co-authored over 300 articles. He's been honored with numerous awards, including the 1993 American Psychological Association Award for Distinguished Contributions to the International Advancement of Psychology. The Henry David papers span the years 1943-2009 and contain materials documenting his professional life, including monographs, photocopied and reprinted journal articles, gray literature, correspondence, subject files, reports, grant proposals, travel brochures, journals, correspondence, conference papers, media clippings, legal reviews of international abortion rights, assessment measures, and questionnaires. It provides extensive documentation of his international family planning research, his international collaborations, his research on adolescents, the legal standing of abortion, abortion as it relates to mental health, and documentation of his work with the Transnational Family Research Institute.
Arrangement
Organized into series: Countries, Adolescents, Legal, Abortion, Research, Miscellaneous, Psychosocial Research, and Abortion and Mental Health Research. There is also a series consisting of unsorted materials.
Biographical / Historical
Henry Philip David (1923-2009) was a pioneering researcher in the field of reproductive behavior and public policy. He is notable for his longitudinal studies on the psychological aspects of abortion, as well as his extensive international collaboration and research. He was the founder (1972) and director of the Transnational Family Research Institute in Bethesda, MD. He wrote and edited 17 books and authored or co-authored over 300 articles. He's been honored with numerous awards, including the 1993 American Psychological Association Award for Distinguished Contributions to the International Advancement of Psychology.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Henry David papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016-2017.
Collection Overview
The Henry David papers span the years 1943-2010 and contain materials documenting his professional life, including monographs, photocopied and reprinted journal articles, grey literature, correspondence, subject files, reports, grant proposals, travel brochures, journals, correspondence, conference papers, media clippings, legal reviews of international abortion rights, assessment measures, and questionnaires. It provides extensive documentation of his international family planning research, his international collaborations, his research on adolescents, the legal standing of abortion, abortion as it relates to mental health, and documentations of his work with the Transnational Family Research Institute.
Abortion -- Psychological research -- Longitudinal studies; Abortion -- Social aspects -- Longitudinal studies; Child development -- Longitudinal studies; Women -- Mental health
- Country Files, 1950-1999, bulk 1970s-1990s; 79 boxes
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by country. David arranged materials for each country into the following files: Abortion, Contraception, Fertility-related, and Miscellaneous. Other subject folders were added as needed for each country.
  - Afghanistan (Box 1)
  - Albania (Box 1)
  - Algeria (Box 2)
  - Argentina (Box 2)
  - Australia (Box 2)
  - Austria (Box 3)
  - Bahrain (Box 3)
  - Bangladesh (Box 3)
  - Barbados (Box 3)
  - Belgium (Box 4)
  - Belize (Box 4)
  - Bermuda (Box 4)
  - Bolivia (Box 4)
  - Botswana (Box 4)
  - Brazil (Box 5)
  - Bulgaria (Box 6)
  - Burkina Faso (Box 7)
  - Burma (Box 7)
  - Burundi (Box 7)
  - Cambodia (Box 7)
  - Cameroon (Box 7)
  - Canada (Box 7)
  - Cape Verde (Box 7)
  - Chad (Box 7)
  - Chile (Box 8)
  - China (Box 9-12)
  - Colombia (Box 13)
  - Costa Rica (Box 13)
  - Cuba (Box 14-20)
  - C.S.S.R. (Czech Republic) (Box 20-21)
  - Dahomey (Box 22)
  - Denmark (Box 22-23)
  - Djibouti (Box 23)
  - Dominican Republic (Box 24)
  - Ecuador (Box 25)
  - Egypt (Box 26)
  - El Salvador (Box 26)
  - Ethiopia (Box 26)
  - Fiji (Box 26)
  - Finland (Box 26)
  - France (Box 26)
  - Gambia (Box 26)
  - Germany (Box 27-28)
  - Ghana (Box 29)
  - Greece (Box 30)
  - Grenada (Box 30)
  - Guadalupe (Box 30)
  - Guatemala (Box 30)
  - Guyana (Box 30)
  - Haiti (Box 30)
  - Honduras (Box 30)
  - Hong Kong (Box 30)
  - Hungary (Box 31-32)
  - Iceland (Box 33)
  - India (Box 33-34)
  - Indonesia (Box 35)
  - Iran (Box 36)
  - Iraq (Box 37)
  - Ireland (Box 37)
  - Israel (Box 37)
  - Italy (Box 37)
  - Ivory Coast (Box 37)
  - Jamaica (Box 38)
  - Japan (Box 38-39)
  - Jordan (Box 40)
  - Kenya (Box 41)
  - North Korea (Box 42)
  - South Korea (Box 42)
  - Korea (Republic of Korea) (Box 43)
  - Kuwait (Box 44)
  - KwaZulu (Box 44)
  - Laos (Box 45)
  - Lebanon (Box 45)
  - Lesotho (Box 45)
  - Liberia (Box 45)
  - Libya (Box 45)
  - Luxembourg (Box 45)
  - Madagascar (Box 45)
  - Malaysia (Box 45)
  - Mali (Box 46)
  - Martinique (Box 46)
  - Mauritania (Box 46)
  - Mauritius (Box 46)
  - Malawi (Box 46)
  - Mexico (Box 47-48)
  - Mongolia (Box 49)
  - Morocco (Box 49)
  - Mozambique (Box 49)
  - Nepal (Box 50)
  - Netherlands (Box 50)
  - New Zeland (Box 51)
  - Nicaragua (Box 51)
  - Niger (Box 51)
  - Nigeria (Box 51)
  - Norway (Box 52)
  - Oman (Box 53)
  - Pakistan (Box 53)
  - Panama (Box 53)
  - Papua New Guinea (Box 53)
  - Paraguay (Box 53)
  - Peru (Box 53)
  - Philippines (Box 54)
  - Poland (Box 55)
  - Portugal (Box 56)
  - Puerto Rico (Box 56)
  - Qatar (Box 56)
  - Reunion (Box 56)
  - Romania (Box 57-59)
  - Russia (Box 60-61)
  - Rwanda (Box 62)
  - St. Vincent (Box 62)
  - Samoa (Box 62)
  - Saudi Arabia (Box 62)
  - Senegal (Box 62)
  - Sierra Leone (Box 62)
  - Singapore (Box 63)
  - Somalia (Box 63)
  - South Africa (Box 63)
  - Spain (Box 63)
  - Sri Lanka (Box 63)
  - Suriname (Box 64)
  - Sudan (Box 64)
  - Swaziland (Box 64)
  - Sweden (Box 64)
  - Switzerland (Box 65)
  - Syria (Box 65)
  - Tahiti (Box 65)
  - Taiwan (Box 65)
  - Tanzania (Box 66)
  - Thailand (Box 66)
  - Togo (Box 67)
  - Tongo (Box 67)
  - Trinidad and Tobago (Box 67)
  - Tunisia (Box 67)
  - Turkey (Box 67)
  - Transkei (Box 67)
  - Uganda (Box 67)
  - United Arab Emirates (Box 67)
  - United Kingdom (Box 68)
  - Uruguay (Box 68)
  - Venezuela (Box 68)
  - Vietnam (Box 69, 119)
  - Yemen (Box 69)
  - Zaire (Box 69)
  - Zambia (Box 69)
  - Zimbabwe (Box 69)
  - Regional, Europe (Box 70-71)
  - Regional, Africa (Box 72)
  - Regional, Latin America and the Caribbean (Box 73)
  - Regional, Asia (Box 74)
  - Regional, World (Box 75)
  - Regional, Baltic Countries (Box 76)
  - Russia, Popov Papers (Box 77)
  - Regional, Middle East (Box 78)
  - Baltic Research (Box 79)
- Adolescents, 1960-1989, bulk 1980s; 15 boxes
  Scope and Contents
  Materials include monographs, questionnaires, surveys, brochures, booklet, clippings, journals, training manuals for health care providers and educators, correspondence, photocopied journal articles and reprints, research notes and research papers.
  - Men (Box 80)
  - World Health Organization/Adolescent fertility (Box 81)
  - Youth health/Reproductive health (Box 82)
  - Adolescent pregnancy (Box 83)
  - Youth reviews I-II (Box 84-85)
  - Sexuality I-III (Box 86-88)
  - Research I-II (Box 89-90)
  - Sexuality IV-V (Box 91-92)
  - Duplicates (Box 94)
  - Newsletters (Box 93)
  - Adolescents (Box 115)
  - Research on adolescents (Box 158)
- Legal, 1940-1999, bulk 1960s-1990s; 7 boxes
  Materials include reprints, photocopies of statues, legal reviews, journals, monographs, photocopied journal articles, many from the International Digest of Health Legislation. The materials focus on legal standing of reproductive rights in countries around the world.
  - International law (Box 95)
  - Legal (Box 96)
  - Laws, Algeria-France (Box 97)
  - Laws, Germany-New Zeland (Box 98)
  - Laws, Nicaragua-Tunisia (Box 99)
  - Laws, Turkey-Zaire (Box 100)
  - United States of America (Box 101)
- Abortion, 1930-1999; 14 boxes
  Materials include correspondence, reprints, photocopies of journal articles, newspaper and magazine clippings, grant proposals, reports, case studies, conference papers, monographs, works by Malcolm Potts, Christopher Tietze, and Warren Hern.
  - Counseling, quality control, administration (Box 112)
  - Abortion research methods (Box 116)
  - Preterm abortions (Box 114)
  - RU-486 (Box 102)
  - Bucharest 1974 World Population Conference (Box 103)
  - Victims (Box 104)
  - Unwanted pregnancy/NAF/NARAL (Box 105)
  - Repeat abortions (Box 133)
  - Opinions, attitudes, and polls (Box 134)
  - Second trimester (Box 135)
  - Abortion, historical and reviews (Box 136)
  - Techniques/Sequelae (Box 137)
  - International conferences (Box 138)
  - Washington, D.C. (Box 139)
  - Various (Box 140)
  - Planned Parenthood in Europe Newsletter (Box 141)
- Research, 1970-2000; 11 boxes
  - American Institutes for Research (AIR)/Transnational Family Research Institute (TFRI)
    - TFRI secretary Mary J. Albert's detailed notes on the daily operations of TFRI (Box 160)
    - TFRI financial information (Box 160)
    - Publications and reports (Box 160)
    - Correspondence with Edwin Fleishman regarding separation of TFRI from AIR (Box 160)
    - David's beginnings with AIR (Box 160)
    - David's dismissal from AIR (Box 160)
    - David's FBI records (Box 160)
      Requested under FOIA
    - Aftermath of AIR/TFRI situation (Box 160)
    - Ford Foundation (Box 160)
    - Herbert L. Friedman (Box 160)
    - Projects and partnerships (Box 160)
    - Frank Engelsmann (Box 160)
    - Workshops and conferences, 1970s-1990s (Box 161)
    - RU486, Emile-Etienne Baulieu, Matie McLauren, Julie DeClerque, IPAS, potential Paris study on psychosocial acceptability (Box 162)
    - Barbara Crane, A Center for Abortion Policy Studies, 1991 (Box 162)
    - Funding: International Reference Center for Abortion Research (IRCAR), Abortion Research Notes, TRFI/IRCAR Library, Don Collins (Scaife Family Trust), Population Council, Sunnen Foundation, Population Crisis Committee, Ford Foundation, Rockefeller Foundation, ARCA Foundation, USAID (withdrawing support), NARAL, IPAS, 1970-1979 (Box 162)
    - Population Council grant, 1992 (Box 162)
    - Grant funding: Moriah Fund, MacArthur, Compton Foundation, Ford, Rockefeller, Wallace Alexander Gerbode Foundation, Weeden, Wallace Global, Goldman Fund, General Service Foundation, Packard (Box 162)
    - Margaret Ives last will and testament (Box 162)
    - Thailand (Box 162)
    - Mexico City (Box 162)
    - Denmark (Box 162)
    - Incentives research and education (Box 162)
    - Cuba, China, Jamaica, Santo Domingo, Jordan (Box 162)
    - Correspondence, 1970s-1990s (Box 162)
    - National Abortion Federation, Frances Kissling (Box 162)
    - Abortion Review, vols. 7-9, 11-21, 56, 59-70, 1982-1998 (Box 163)
    - David articles, including early work, 1950-2000 (Box 163)
    - TRFI/David's financial records (Box 164)
  - David's Field Notes and Background Research
    - HIV/AIDS, 1985-2002 (Box 119)
    - Spiral-bound notebooks filled with handwritten research, travel, and field notes (Box 148)
    - Background information for David's projects in China, along with correspondence with Wang Fang and Baochang Gu (Box 148)
    - Correspondence, 2009 (Box 149)
    - Transnational Family Research Institute records, including IRS correspondence and board meetings (Box 149)
    - Population and Development International records and publications (Box 149)
    - Documentation of Population and Community Development Association's work in Thailand (Box 149)
    - Illinois Religious Coalition for Abortion Rights records, including meetings (Box 149)
    - David's papers and notes on abortion and mental health (Box 150)
    - Population Association of America meeting materials, 1973 (Box 150)
    - David's course materials and lectures (Box 150)
    - Documentation and correspondence concerning the hearing before the House of Representatives on the medical and psychological impact of abortion (Box 151)
    - Notes and documentation on the 2006 Prague Study (Box 151)
    - Documentation of the American Psychological Association Mental Health and Abortion Task Force, 2008 (Box 151)
    - David's email correspondence, 2005-2007 (Box 151)
    - Gray literature and other research on abortion and family planning in Asia (Box 151)
    - David's research papers (published and draft), 1947-1960; 1991-2008 (Box 152)
      Arranged chronologically
    - Bibliography and published works, 1948-1961; 1959-1961 (Box 152)
    - Papers on Soviet women in Israel (Box 152)
    - David's research papers (published and draft), 1981-1989 (Box 153-154)
    - Aral Sea project documentation (Box 154)
    - MacArthur Fellow information (Box 154)
    - Oral Ataniyazova correspondence and financial information (Box 154)
    - Mohammad Zakaria Pezeshki (Box 154)
    - Asya Posadskaya's MacArthur Grant (Box 154)
    - Michai Viravaidya correspondence and information (Box 154)
    - Rebecca Gomperts correspondence and Women on Waves materials (Box 154)
    - Anatoly Vishnevsky correspondence (Box 154)
    - Nadia Azhgikhina correspondence and information (Box 154)
    - Russian Association of Women Journalists reports (Box 154)
    - Correspondence, including Warren Hern, Warren Miller, Nadia Azhgikhina, Andrej Popov, Michele Rivkin-Fish, and IPAS/Julia Cleaver (Box 155)
    - Transnational Family Research International grant for IPAS collection development (Box 155)
    - World Federation for Mental Health publications, 1960-1969 (Box 155)
    - Correspondence, Population Reference Bureau, Ford Foundation grant (Box 155)
    - David publications, 1960-1969 (Box 155)
    - TFRI USSR projects, Andrej A. Popov, Michele Rivkin-Fish (Box 155)
    - David publications, 1950s-1980s (Box 156)
    - Correspondence, Szondi research, 1950-1959 (Box 156)
    - David's publications (continuation from boxes 153-154) (Box 157)
    - "They Know It All": a manual for those interested in sex education work - International Population Federation, 1990 (Box 157)
    - David publications and presentations on abortion and family planning (Box 158)
    - TFRI financial records on the use of the Ives Fund (Box 158)
    - Research notes and presentations on various countries (Poland, Denmark, Romania, Mexico) (Box 158)
    - David's research (continued from box 157) (Box 159)
    - David's publications and other abortion-related literature (Box 159)
  - Abortion and Mental Health Research, 21 boxes
    - International Population Conference papers: 1973, 1977, 1981, 1985, 1993 (Box 124)
    - Sundhedsstyrelsen Vitalstatistik, 1980-1992 (Box 123)
    - Annual Review of Population Law, vol. 10-18 (Box 123)
    - Foreign language books (Box 120-122)
    - Research papers (published and draft) and news coverage on the social and psychological effects of abortion, as well as post abortion, postnatal, and postpartum mental health (Box 144)
    - Materials published over several decades by Henry David and others (Box 144)
    - A report on the Psychological Aftermath of Abortion, presented to C. Everett Koop by the National Right to Life Committee; also contains Henry David's testimony on behalf of the APHA, 1987 (Box 144)
    - Published research and gray literature on population policy and reproductive health (Box 145)
    - Abortion Review, vols. 51-52, 1994 (Box 145)
    - Abortion Review incorporating Abortion Research Notes vols. 56-58, 64, 1995-1997 (Box 145)
    - Abortion Research Notes, vols. 1-22 (some missing; some duplicates), 1972-1993 (Box 145)
    - Coverage of Henry David's donation to the American Psychological Foundation (APF), including newsletters and correspondence between David, APF, and grant recipients (Box 145)
    - Henry David publications on postabortion mental health and the Prague study (Box 145)
    - Barbara Crane's proposal for a "new international initiative to promote reproductive health and safe abortion services", 1990 (Box 145)
    - Correspondence concerning the FDA hold on trials for quinacrine sterilization (Box 145)
    - Book reviews about David and his works (Box 145)
    - Journal articles related to psychology and abortion (Box 145)
    - Published research (most by or affiliated with David), gray literature, journals and newsletters, and news coverage on abortion, contraception, and family planning, 1960s-1990s (Box 146)
    - News coverage and gray literature on the politics of abortion in the U.S. (Box 147)
    - Materials on the family, family planning, reproductive health, and abortion in Iran, the Middle East, and Islam (Box 147)
    - Research on the effects of abortion and denied abortion (Box 147)
  - Researchers and International NGOs
    - FHI Conference, Vietnam, 1994 (Box 119)
    - Christopher Tietze, 1974 (Box 132)
    - Malcolm Potts, 1974-1975 (Box 106-107)
    - Christopher Tietze, 1975-1985 (Box 108)
    - Ipas (Box 113)
    - World Health Organization/Europe (Box 109)
    - Warren Hern (Box 111)
    - Center for Disease Control: Abortion reports, statistics (Box 110)
  - Women
    - Motherhood: Pregnancy, maternal mortality, childbirth, childrearing (Box 118)
    - Politics (Box 118)
    - Legal (Box 118)
    - Socioeconomic development (Box 118)
    - Employment (Box 118)
    - Religion (Box 118)
    - Education (Box 118)
    - Marriage and relationships (Box 118)
    - Magazine and newspaper clippings, 1991-2002 (Box 118)
    - Family planning (Box 117)
    - General health (Box 117)
    - Mental health (Box 117)
    - Reproductive health (Box 117)
    - Violence against women: domestic, sexual, FGM (Box 117)
    - Feminism and gender issues (Box 117)
    - Sexuality (Box 117)
    - Population and development (Box 117)
- Psychosocial Workshops, 1973-2010; 2 boxes
  - Psychosocial Workshop Writings (Box 165)
  - History (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop agendas, participant lists, and schedules (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Dallas, TX, 2010-04-13-2010-04-14 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Detroit, MI, 2009 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, New Orleans, LA, 2008 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Los Angeles, CA, 2006 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Philadelphia, PA, 2005 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Boston, MA, 2004 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Minneapolis, MN, 2003 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Atlanta, GA, 2002 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Washington, D.C., 2001 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Los Angeles, CA, 2000 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, New York, NY, 1999 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Chicago, IL, 1998 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Washington, D.C., 1997 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, New Orleans, LA, 1996 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, San Francisco, CA, 1995 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Miami, FL, 1994 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Cincinnati, OH, 1993 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Denver, CO, 1992 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Washington, D.C., 1991 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Toronto, Canada, 1990 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Baltimore, MD, 1989 (Box 165)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, New Orleans, LA, 1988 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Chicago, IL, 1987 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, San Francisco, CA, 1986 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Boston, MA, 1985 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Minneapolis, MN, 1984 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Pittsburgh, PA, 1983 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, San Diego, CA, 1982 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Washington, D.C., 1981 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Denver, CO, 1980 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Philadelphia, PA, 1979 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Atlanta, GA, 1978 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, St. Louis, MO, 1977 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, Montreal, Canada, 1976 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, 1975 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, New York, NY, 1974 (Box 166)
  - Psychosocial Workshop, New Orleans, LA, 1973 (Box 166)
  - Abortion Research Workshop, 1974 (Box 166)
  - Family photo slides (Box 166)
- Unsorted Materials, 1943-2009, bulk 1960s-2000s; 9 boxes
  - Box A, 1960-1999 (Box 125)
    Topics include: abortion, contraception, women's health, gender roles, family and marriage. Countries: U.S. (bulk), Cuba, Peru. People: Warren Hern, Malcolm Potts, Christopher Tietze.
  - Box B, 1970s-2009, bulk 1970s-2000 (Box 126)
    Topics: Abortion, abortion law, contraception, fertility, gender roles, mental health. Contries: China, Thailand, Sweden, Philippines, Tahiti, Sudan, Tanzania, Syria, Iceland, Ireland, South Korea, Jamaica, Lichtenstein, Zambia, United States
  - Box C, 1990s (Box 127)
    Topics: Abortion, contraception, family planning, women's empowerment, women's health, mental health, female genital mutilation, gender roles, men/male roles, HIV/AIDS/STIs, sex education, sexual abuse/exploitation, postabortion care. Places: Africa, Europe, US, Russia
  - Box D, 1943-2000, bulk 1970s-2000 (Box 128)
    Topics: Family planning, contraception, abortion, population issues. Places: US, Europe, China, Sri Lanka, Trinidad and Tobago, India
  - Box E, 1960s-1970s (Box 129)
    Topics: Abortion, family planning, marriage and family, population studies, research methodology, sexuality, sex knowledge/experience, social science/general practice psychology, research methods. Places: Korea, China, East Africa, Costa Rica, Chile, United States. People: James Jaccard, Murray Straus, Harlan Strauss
  - Box F, 1970s (Box 130)
    Topics: Abortion attitudes, abortion seekers, family planning, marriage and family, behavior, population studies, research methodology. Places: United States, Hungary, Ygoslavia, Singapore, Japan, France, Nigeria, Jamaica. People: John R.P. French, Earl Schaeffer, Harrison Gough, Warren Miller
  - Box G, 1970s-1980s (Box 131)
    Topcs: Abortion law, reproductive law, family planning, demographic transition, population development. Places: Romania, United States, Eastern Europe, Russia, Germany, Africa, Kenya, Cuba
  - Box H, 1970s-1990s (Box 142)
    Topics: Abortion, abortion law, quinacrine sterilization, contraception (male and female), contraceptive choice/use, misoprostal, mifepristone. Places: United States (bulk), Saudi Arabia, Russia, Africa, Kenya, Cameroon, Mauritius, Ghana, Latin America, South America, Cuba, Eastern Europe. People: Rebecca Cook, Sally Epstein, Donald Collins, Stephen Mumford
  - Box I, 1990s-2000s (Box 143)
    Topic: Abortion, various aspects. Places: United States, Israel, Puerto Rico, Australia. People: Stanley Henshaw